<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Ala Eddine GRINE</title>
    <link>https://alagrine.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Ala Eddine GRINE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 11:14:48 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alagrine.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Churn prediction and machine learning at scale with Pyspark and Spark MLlib.</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p4-sparkify-churn-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p4-sparkify-churn-prediction/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project is to build a binary classification model using Pyspark ML to predict churn. The project is divided into the following sections:
Use a small subset (on a local machine) to perform exploratory data analysis and build a prototype machine learning model. Scale up: use a medium dataset (on a local machine) to see how our model works on a larger dataset. Deploy a cluster in the cloud with AWS using the big dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendations with IBM</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p3-recommendations-with-ibm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p3-recommendations-with-ibm/</guid>
      <description>This project is part of Udacity&amp;rsquo;s Data Science Nanodegree Program in collaboration with IBM. The aim of this project is to build a recommendation system for users of the IBM Watson community.
A dataset of 5149 users, 714 articles and about 46K interactions is used to develop this RecSys.
The project is divided into the following sections:
Build an ETL pipeline to extract, clean and load the data to a SQLite database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disaster Response Project</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p2-disaster-response-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p2-disaster-response-project/</guid>
      <description>This project is part of Udacity&amp;rsquo;s Data Science Nanodegree Program in collaboration with Appen (formally Figure 8). The goal of this project is to build a model for an API that classifies messages received in real time during a disaster event, so that messages can be sent to the correct disaster response agency.
A dataset of thousands of real-world messages during disaster events is used to build this model.
The Project is divided in the following sections:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boston AirBnB Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p1-boston-airbnb-dataanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/post/p1-boston-airbnb-dataanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Throughout this project, I was interested in using Boston Airbnb Open dataset, available here, to answer the following questions:
How does seasonality affect AirBnB prices in Boston? How does location affect AirBnB prices? What are the most important features to predict AirBnB prices? What is the relationship between reviews and price? Link to GitHub repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a certified data scientist and network analytics manager with expertise in programming languages such as Python and Java, SQL databases, and data visualisation tools such as Tableau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://alagrine.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alagrine.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>Follow me on these social media platforms.
Platform URL Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/ala-eddine-grine Github: https://github.com/AlaGrine Medium: https://medium.com/@alaeddine.grine Gmail: alaeddine.grine@gmail.com </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
